Privacy Policy
==============

At Customer Union for Ethical Banking, we’re committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This Privacy Policy explains when and why we collect personal information about people who visit our website, how we use it, the conditions under which we may disclose it to others and how we keep it secure.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes.

Any questions regarding this Policy and our privacy practices should be sent by email to [info@saveourbank.coop](mailto:info@saveourbank.coop) or by writing to:

Customer Union for Ethical Banking, Unit 21, 41 Old Birley Street, Manchester, M15 5RF, UK.

Alternatively, you can telephone 0161 226 2929.

Who are we?
-----------

The Customer Union for Ethical Banking (CUEB) is an independent, not-for profit cooperative. Its members are Co-op Bank customers who support the aims of the cooperative. CUEB is keeping a constant eye on the Co-op Bank, ensuring that it sticks to its ethical principles and aiming eventually to help it return to cooperative ownership. CUEB was set up by the founders of the Save Our Bank campaign.

We keep our members and supporters informed with an email newsletter and our website. We meet with the bank and other organisations to help us achieve our aims. CUEB members pay a small subscription to help us continue this work.

How do we collect information from you?
---------------------------------------

* We collect browsing information on your IP address, what pages are accessed and when. This is done via cookies.
* We collect personal information such as your name and email address when you sign up as a supporter of the campaign.
* We collect personal information such as your name, email address, postal address and phone number when you become a member of CUEB.
* We do **not** store payment information. If you pay your membership subscription using Direct Debit, credit or debit card details or Paypal, the details of your card or account are not stored on our systems but are transmitted directly to our third party payment processors: GoCardless, Stripe or PayPal, each of whom specialise in the secure online capture and processing of payment transactions.

How is your information used?
-----------------------------

We use your information to:

* Process a subscription to become a member of the Customer Union;
* Notify you of changes to our services;
* Send you email newsletters, generally not more than once a month, which include information about the campaigns;
* Monitor how you use the website, and how you got to the website;
* Understand the views of members and supporters who take part in surveys.

We review our retention periods for personal information on a regular basis. We are legally required to hold some types of information to fulfil our statutory obligations. We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity, or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with us.

Who has access to your information?
-----------------------------------

We will not sell or rent your information to third parties.

We will not share your information with third parties for marketing purposes.

Third Party Service Providers working on our behalf
---------------------------------------------------

We may pass your information to our third party service providers, agents subcontractors and other associated organisations for the purposes of completing tasks and providing services to you on our behalf (for example to process subscriptions and send you mailings). However, when we use third party service providers, we disclose only the personal information that is necessary to deliver the service and we have a contract in place that requires them to keep your information secure and not to use it for their own direct marketing purposes.

CUEB uses the following Third Party Service Providers:

**Mailchimp**

We use Mailchimp to send email newsletters to our supporters and members. This means that personal details of supporters and members including name, email address and membership status are stored on Mailchimp’s servers in the USA. Mailchimp is a US company that specialises in the transmission of email to large mailing lists. Mailchimp has comprehensive systems to ensure that subscriber details are kept secure.

Your choices
------------

You have a choice about whether or not you wish to receive information from us. We give subscribers and supporters the option to opt in to receiving email newsletters from us about our campaigns and general activities.

We will not otherwise contact you for marketing purposes by phone or text message unless you have given your prior consent.

You can change your marketing preferences at any time by contacting us by email: [info@saveourbank.coop](mailto:info@saveourbank.coop) or telephone on 0161 226 2929.

You can also opt out of receiving email newsletters at any time using the ‘unsubscribe’ button at the bottom of every email sent.

How you can access and update your information
----------------------------------------------

The accuracy of your information is important to us.

If you are a CUEB member you can update your information by logging into the website and editing your profile.

If you are not a member but wish to update your email address please follow the link at the bottom of every email from us.

Alternatively if you change email address, or any of the other information we hold is inaccurate or out of date, please email us at: [info@saveourbank.coop](mailto:info@saveourbank.coop). Or write to us at Customer

Union for Ethical Banking, Unit 21, 41 Old Birley Street, Manchester, M15 5RF, UK or call us on 0161 226 2929.

Security precautions in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of your information
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

When you give us personal information, we take steps to ensure that it’s treated securely. Any sensitive information (such as credit or debit card details) is encrypted. When you are on a secure page, a lock icon will appear on web browsers such as Microsoft Internet Explorer.

Non-sensitive details (your email address etc.) are transmitted normally over the Internet, and this can never be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your information, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. Where we have given (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our websites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

Use of 'cookies'
----------------

Like many other websites, the Save Our Bank and Customer Union website uses cookies. 'Cookies' are small pieces of information sent by the web server to your computer and stored to allow that website to recognise you when you visit.

The cookies we use are only those that are necessary for the functioning of the Save Our Bank site. For example, we use cookies to remember the whether you have logged in. Under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), these cookies are classed as 'necessary' and are not used for any marketing purposes. This is why there is no 'Accept cookies' function on the Save Our Bank site.

Links to other websites
-----------------------

Our website may contain links to websites run by other organisations. This privacy policy applies only to our website‚ so we encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit. We cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other sites even if you access them using links from our website.  
In addition, if you linked to our website from a third party site, we cannot be responsible for the privacy policies and practices of the owners and operators of that third party site and recommend that you check the policy of that third party site.

16 or Under
-----------

We are concerned to protect the privacy of children aged 16 or under. If you are aged 16 or under‚ please get your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide us with personal information.

Your rights
-----------

Under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and The Data Protection Act 2018 (DPA) you have a number of rights with regard to your personal data. You have the right to:

* Be informed about the collection and use of your personal data
* Access to your personal data
* Rectification of your personal data
* Have the personal data we hold on you erased
* Restrict the processing of your personal data
* Object to the processing of your personal data
* Have your personal data transferred to another controller/processor
* Identity and contact details of controller and data protection contact

Customer Union for Ethical Banking is the controller and processor of data for the purposes of the DPA 18 and GDPR.

If you have any concerns as to how your data is processed you can contact:  Shaun Fensom (Data Protection Contact) at shaun \[at\] saveourbank.coop or you can write to this individual using the address of:  

Customer Union for Ethical Banking   
Unit 21, 41 Old Birley Street   
Manchester   
M15 5RF  
United Kingdom

If you are unhappy with how we are using your information and are unable to resolve the issue with us, you can raise the matter with the Information Commissioners Office by calling 0303 123 1113 or visiting ico.org.uk/concerns

Review of this Policy
---------------------

We keep this Policy under regular review. This Policy was last updated in November 2019.

#SaveOurBank

Customer Union for Ethical Banking  
Unit 21, 41 Old Birley Street, Manchester M15 5RF  
A cooperative society registered with the FCA number 4161

You can see our [privacy policy here](https://saveourbank.coop/privacy-policy)

The Save Our Bank campaign is backed by [Ethical Consumer magazine](http://www.ethicalconsumer.org/home/saveourbank.aspx)
